# Tzu-Sheng Kuo

(650) 391-5684 ⋈ tskuo@stanford.edu 🕆 tskuo.github.io

I create interactive systems that envision or reshape the design of future technology to support human well-being. My research interest in human-computer interaction is at the intersection of digital fabrication, sensing and interaction techniques, and application to digital healthcare, behavior change, and accessibility.

#### Education

Stanford University.

Master of Science in Electrical Engineering, GPA: 4.00/4.00

National Taiwan University (NTU). 2014 - 2019

Bachelor of Science in Electrical Engineering, GPA: 4.25/4.30, Summa Cum Laude (Top 1%)

## Research Experience

## **Human-Computer Interaction**

2019 - Present Stanford HCl Group, Stanford, CA.

Advisors: Prof. James Landay, Prof. Elizabeth Murnane

- o Proposed a design framework for interactive systems that adopt natural elements to support user well-being
- o Resulted in one publication in submission to CHI 2021
- 2017 2019 Interactive Graphics Lab, NTU, Taiwan.

Advisors: Prof. Bing-Yu Chen, Prof. Xing-Dong Yang

- o Designed two pneumatic interfaces that emulate physical objects to provide haptic feedback in VR
- o Designed a software tool with an autocomplete feature to assist makers in building breadboard circuits
- o Resulted in three publications at UIST 2018, UIST 2019, and CHI 2019

## Computer Vision & Machine Learning

2017 - 2019 Vision and Learning Lab, NTU, Taiwan.

Advisor: Prof. Yu-Chiang Frank Wang

- o Modified DeepLabv3+ and proposed a loss function for semantic segmentation on satellite imagery
- o Resulted in one publication at DeepGlobe Workshop in CVPR 2018

#### Signal Processing

Multimedia Processing and Communications Lab, NTU, Taiwan.

Advisor: Prof. Homer H. Chen

- o Approximated the temporal variation of gaze fixation to estimate the depth map of indoor spaces based on eye vergence
- Resulted in one publication at ICIP 2018

### Peer-Reviewed Publications

CHI 2021 Tzu-Sheng Kuo. Kelsey Wang, Sarah L. Billington, James A. Landay, and Elizabeth L. Murnane. 2021. Biophilic Technology: Exploring the Application of Biophilic Principles to the Design of Digital Interfaces. In Submission to Proceedings of (under review) the 2021 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI '21). ACM, New York, NY, USA. [under review]

UIST 2019 Shan-Yuan Teng, Cheng-Lung Lin, Chi-huan Chiang, Tzu-Sheng Kuo, Liwei Chan, Da-Yuan Huang, and Bing-Yu Chen.

2019. TilePoP: Tile-type Pop-up Prop for Virtual Reality. In Proceedings of the 32nd Annual ACM Symposium on User Interface Software and Technology (UIST '19). ACM, New York, NY, USA, 639-649.

**Best Paper Honorable Mention [PDF]** 

CHI 2019 Jo-Yu Lo, Da-Yuan Huang, Tzu-Sheng Kuo, Chen-Kuo Sun, Jun Gong, Teddy Seyed, Xing-Dong Yang, and Bing-Yu Chen.

2019. AutoFritz: Autocomplete for Prototyping Virtual Breadboard Circuits. In Proceedings of the 2019 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI '19). ACM, New York, NY, USA, Paper 403, 1-13.

**Best Paper Honorable Mention [PDF]** 

Shan-Yuan Teng, Tzu-Sheng Kuo, Chi Wang, Chi-huan Chiang, Da-Yuan Huang, Liwei Chan, and Bing-Yu Chen. 2018. UIST 2018 PuPoP: Pop-up Prop on Palm for Virtual Reality. In Proceedings of the 31st Annual ACM Symposium on User Interface Software and Technology (UIST '18). ACM, New York, NY, USA, 5–17. [PDF]

CVPRW 2018 Tzu-Sheng Kuo\*, Keng-Sen Tseng\*, Jia-Wei Yan\*, Yen-Cheng Liu, and Yu-Chiang Frank Wang. 2018. Deep Aggregation Net for Land Cover Classification. In IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition Workshops (CVPRW '18). Salt Lake City, UT, pp. 252-256. \*The authors contributed equally. [PDF]

ICIP 2018 Tzu-Sheng Kuo, Kuang-Tsu Shih, Sheng-Lung Chung, and Homer H. Chen. 2018. Depth from Gaze. In 25th IEEE International Conference on Image Processing (ICIP '18). Athens, pp. 2910–2914. [PDF]

#### Posters and Demos

UIST 2020 **Tzu-Sheng Kuo** and Eric Rawn. 2020. Let It Rip! Using Velcro for Acoustic Labeling. In *The Adjunct Publication of the 33rd Annual ACM Symposium on User Interface Software and Technology* (UIST '20). [PDF]

(a project mentored by Prof. Michael Bernstein at Stanford)

HCOMP 2020 Tzu-Sheng Kuo, McArdle Hankin, Miranda Li, Andrew Ying, and Cathy Wang. 2020. Assessing Political Bias using

• Crowdsourced Pairwise Comparisons. In *Proceeding of the 8th AAAI Conference on Human Computation and Crowdsourcing* (HCOMP '20). [PDF]

**Best Poster Award** 

(a project mentored by Prof. Maneesh Agrawala at Stanford)

## **Teaching Experience**

- 2018 Teaching Assistant, Computer Vision: from Recognition to Geometry Instructor: Prof. Yu-Chiang Frank Wang
- 2018 Teaching Assistant, Deep Learning for Computer Vision Instructor: Prof. Yu-Chiang Frank Wang
- 2017 Teaching Assistant, Machine Learning Instructor: Prof. Hung-Yi Lee
- 2017 Teaching Assistant, Signals and Systems Instructor: Prof. Lin-Shan Lee
- 2016 Teaching Assistant, Electronics I Instructor: Prof. Liang-Hung Lu

## Honors and Awards

- 2020 Stanford Graduate Student Research Assistantship
- 2018 Phi Tau Phi Scholastic Honor Society Honorary Membership Graduated top 1% in NTU EECS Department
- 2014 2018 **Dean's List (5 times)** Top 5% GPA in each semester
  - 2018 Chien Shih-Liang Memorial Scholarship Given to two students in NTU EECS Department each year
  - 2017 Taiwan Ministry of Science and Technology Research Grant
  - 2017 Irving T. Ho Memorial Scholarship Given to one senior student in NTU EE Department each year

## **University Service**

#### 2020 - Present HCI Qualifying Exam DEI Proposal Group

In light of the Black Lives Matter movement and anti-East Asian racism due to COVID-19, I co-lead an initiative at Stanford HCI Group to add readings that center on diversity, equity, and inclusion to the Ph.D. qualifying exam.

### 2020 - Present Graduate Residence Community Associate

I work with the Stanford Graduate Life Office and other community associates on promoting wellness and a sense of community in graduate residences with 1200+ students by coordinating social events that center on cultural diversity.

# Leadership Experience

#### 2016 - 2018 Founder, Makerspace of NTUEE &

My team and I founded a makerspace to assist students with their side projects. During COVID-19, our students developed a system that was deployed across the campus to automatically detect and track people's forehead temperatures.

2017 Chair, MakeNTU Makeathon &

My team and I launched the first nationwide makeathon in Taiwan with 200 participants and 70K USD in sponsorship. I led 60 students and cooperated with the Taipei City Government and 22 companies such as Google and Microsoft.

2016 - 2017 Director, Academic Department of NTUEE Student Association §

I led a team of 30 students to organize various university events, including research competitions, university fairs, and NTUEE+ alumni mixers for 800+ students in the EE department.

# Work Experience

- 2019 Mandatory Military Service, Taiwan.
- 2017 Software Engineering Intern, Cadence Design Systems, Inc., San Jose, CA.
  - o My code for Gate-Level and RTL circuit design automation and equivalence checking was checked-in for production.

#### **Technical Skills**

Technical Skills Python, C++/C#, Matlab, Tensorflow, PyTorch, React, Javascript, CSS, HTML, Unity, OpenCV, Verilog, etc.

Languages English (fluent), Mandarin (native), Taiwanese (native)